Guide to the Maxine Kumin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Maxine Kumin papers
1965-2005
YCAL MSS 734
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
49.42
(68 boxes)
The collection contains writings, correspondence, and other materials documenting Maxine Kumin's literary work and professional and public activities since 1960.
Kumin, Maxine, 1925-2014
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James S. Jaffe Books on various funds, 1990-2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 43-47, 54, 61-65 (sound and video recordings, computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of audio recordings and electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Maxine Kumin (1925-)
Maxine Kumin was born Maxine Winokur on 6 June 1925 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and educated at Radcliffe College (1946, 1948). Kumin worked as an instructor and lecturer in English and Tufts University for several years between 1958 and 1968 and has held visting appointments at other institutions around the country since the 1970s. She is the author of numerous children's books, poetry collections, essay and short story collections, and novels, and her many awards include the Pulitzer Prize (1973) for Up Country, American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters Award for excellence in literature (1980), Poets' Prize (1994) and Aiken Talyor Poetry Prize (1995) for Looking For Luck, and Ruth Lilly Poetry Prize (1999). Since 1976, she and her husband have lived on a farm in Warner, New Hampshire.
Biographical information taken from "Maxine Kumin." Contemporary Women Poets. Gale, 1998. Biography In Context. Web. 13 June 2013.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains writings, correspondence, and other materials documenting Maxine Kumin's literary work and professional and public activities since 1960. Writings include drafts, proofs, and other materials relating to book-length and shorter works. Kumin wrote children's books, poetry collections, essay and short story collections, and novels, and files can be found for works dating from the early children's book A Winter Friend (1961) to the late collection of poems, Still to Mow (2007). Large files can be found for a variety of work: The Abduction (1971), The Long Approach (1985), Looking For Luck (1992), Women, Animals, and Vegetables (1994), Selected Poems 1960-1990 (1997), Quit Monks or Die (1999), Inside the Halo and Beyond the Journey (1999), Always Beginning (2000), and Jack and Other New Poems (2005).
Correspondence in the collection can be found with writers, literary critics, publishers, and family. Correspondents include: Dudley Fitts, William Meredith, Howard Nemerov, Anne Sexton, and the publishers Harper & Row, McGraw-Hill, W. W. Norton, Viking, and North Point Press. The March 2013 Acquisition contains a large file of correspondence, dating from 1945 and 1946, between Maxine Kumin and her husband Victor.
Other materials appear chiefly to document Kumin's professional and public actitivities. There are financial and legal records, such as contracts and permissions, correspondence and documents relating to speaking engagements and participation on literary juries and in the Bread Loaf Writers' Conference; printed materials, including reviews and publicity; audiovisual materials, including both sound and video recordings of readings by Kumin, interviews, and other cultural events; and personal papers, such as calendars and photographs.
Arrangement
Organized into seven groupings: March 1990 Acquisition, May 1995 Acquisition, March 2001 Acquisition, January 2005 Acquisition, August 2006 Acquisition, January 2012 Acquisition, and March 2013 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Fitts, Dudley, 1903-1968; Kumin, Maxine, 1925-2014; Meredith, William, 1919-2007; Nemerov, Howard, 1920-1991; Sexton, Anne, 1928-1974; Bread Loaf Writers' Conference of Middlebury College; Harper & Row, Publishers; McGraw-Hill Publishing Company; North Point Press; W.W. Norton & Company; Viking Press
- March 1990 Acquisition, 1940-1987; 17.12; (20 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Files are not arranged in any particular order.
  Scope and Contents
  The March 1990 Acquisition includes writings, correspondence, and other professional and personal papers. Writings include drafts, proofs, and other materials relating to book-length and shorter works. Kumin wrote children's books, poetry collections, essay and short story collections, and novels, and files can be found for A Winter Friend (1961), The Abduction (1971), The Designated Heir (1974), and The Long Approach (1985), among others. There is also correspondence with writers, literary critics, and publishers, including Dudley Fitts, William Meredith, Howard Nemerov, Anne Sexton, Atlantic Monthly, Poetry Magazine, Saturday Review, Harper and Row, McGraw-Hill, and W. W. Norton. Other materials chiefly document Kumin's professional actitivities, such as speaking engagements and participation on literary juries and in the Bread Loaf Writers' Conference.
  General note
  Former call number: Uncat Za MS 131.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund and the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 1990.
  - The Abduction, 1960s; 9 (Box 1)
  - The Long Approach, 1986 (Box 1)
  - In Deep, 1986-1987; 3 (Box 1)
  - A Winter Friend, 1961 (Box 1)
  - When Mother Was Young, 1970 (Box 1)
  - "What Color Is Caesar?", undated (Box 1)
  - Why Can't We Live Together Like Civilized Human Beings?, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - Our Ground Time Here Will Be Brief, 1983, undated; 3 (Box 1)
  - House, Bridge, Fountain, Gate, 1976 July 26 (Box 2)
  - Designated Heir, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Why Can't We Live Like Civilized Human Beings?, reviews, publicity, etc., 1982 (Box 3)
  - Holmes, John, 1957-1961 (Box 3)
  - NJ, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
  - Russell Volkening, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Bulgaria, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Lamont, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Serving as judge, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Tear sheets of articles and poems, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
  - Recommendations--also blurbs, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Curtis Brown, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Requests--miscellaneous, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Income, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Requests for interviews--requests for reviews, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Curtis Brown, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Our Ground Time Here Will Be Brief, Why Can't We Live Together Like Civilized Human Beings, publicity, blurbs, reviews, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Requests for poems, article reprint rights, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
  - Speaking engagements NO, 1977-1982 (Box 3)
  - Library of Congress--current correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Speaking or teaching--no or doubtful, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - Recommendations (for jobs, fellowships, blurbs), 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Students, would-be writers, etc. from speaking engagements, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Our Ground Time Here Will Be Brief, copyright reversions and assignments, 1970-1981 (Box 4)
  - Library of Congress, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Council of Scholars, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Speaking completed, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Friends who are primarily writers--frequent correspondence, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Anne Sexton, 1963-1975 (Box 4)
  - Sexton--obituaries, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Sexton--condolences, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Sexton, Anne, 1974-1979 (Box 4)
  - Houghton Mifflin--Sexton introduction, 1980-1981; 2 (Box 4)
  - Writers, etc., established--infrequently heard from, 1978-1985; 3 (Box 4)
  - Friends, primarily writers, frequent correspondence, 1978-1981; 2 (Box 4)
  - Pulitzer congratulations, 1973; 2 (Box 5)
  - Writers miscellaneous, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Tidbits from other writers, 1971 April 20 (Box 5)
  - Writers--former students, Breadloafers, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Writers--well known, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Tidbits--other writers, undated (Box 5)
  - Students, writers, etc. from speaking engagements, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Writers--miscellaneous, 1971-1974 (Box 5)
  - Friends, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Writers--former students, ex-Breadloafers, etc., 1975 (Box 5)
  - Friends (non-professional poets)--old. frequent correspondence, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Writers--established, 1975 (Box 5)
  - The Wizard's Tears, 1972-1976 (Box 5)
  - "What Color Is Caesar?", undated (Box 5)
  - Bulgaria story--notes, drafts, undated (Box 5)
  - Why Can't We Live Together Like Civilized Human Beings?, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Our Ground Time Here Will Be Brief, undated; 2 (Box 5)
  - Manuscript of The Retrieval System, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Worksheets-- The Retrieval System, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Worksheets-- The Retrieval System, 1976 (Box 6)
  - The Retrieval System --Manuscripts and galleys, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Copy-edited transcript of The Designated Heir, undated (Box 6)
  - House, Bridge, Fountain, Gate, 1975-1976, undated; 2 (Box 6)
  - "Cowboy and Pest & The Runaway Goat", 1965, undated (Box 6)
  - Copy of thesis on Dostoievsky, undated (Box 6)
  - "Sebastian and The Dragon", 1972-1974 (Box 6)
  - Grandmother in the Red North End, 1966-1968 (Box 6)
  - Great-grandmother children's story; also grandmother story, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Mother, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - The Nightmare Factory, 1969 November 18 (Box 6)
  - Manuscript of The Nightmare Factory, 1969 November 18 (Box 6)
  - McGraw-Hill-- Joey and the Birthday Present, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Proofs-- The Privilege, undated (Box 6)
  - "Three to Vote" (Play), 1962, undated (Box 6)
  - Faraway Farm, 1966-1967, undated (Box 6)
  - The Designated Heir, undated (Box 6)
  - Poetry Society of America, 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - G.P. Putnam, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
  - Radcliffe Quarterly, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Radcliffe 25th Reunion, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Radcliffe College, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Tufts--elegy, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Speaking engagements, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Speaking engagements and serving as judge, 1962-1968; 2 (Box 7)
  - Tufts College, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
  - English I notes--Tufts, 1958-1960, undated (Box 7)
  - Ascher, Bob, 1960-1970 (Box 7)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Audience, 1970-1972 (Box 7)
  - Bread Loaf--old, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - Bread Loaf, 1970-1972 (Box 7)
  - Bread Loaf Conference, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Bread Loaf, 1968 (Box 7)
  - California, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Crowell, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1968-1971; 2 (Box 7)
  - Family, 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - Fan mail, 1967-1972; 2 (Box 7)
  - Friends, 1962-1972; 2 (Box 7)
  - Hall, Jules, 1971-1972, undated (Box 7)
  - Harper & Row, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Harper & Row, 1967-1969 (Box 8)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1966-1972 (Box 8)
  - Hudson Review, 1960-1969 (Box 8)
  - Perry London, 1966-1969 (Box 8)
  - Council on the Arts and Humanities, Massachusetts, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - The Massachusetts Review, 1969-1972 (Box 8)
  - McGraw-Hill, 1973 April (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous magazines, 1962-1972 (Box 8)
  - National Council on the Arts--grant, 1966-1970 (Box 8)
  - Friends, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Papinchak, 1974-1976 (Box 8)
  - Microscope--negotiations for new book, 1976 (Box 8)
  - The Nightmare Factory / reviews, etc., 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Up Country / reviews, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
  - W.W. Norton (William McMorris), 1964-1970 (Box 8)
  - Paris Review, undated (Box 8)
  - The Passions of Uxport, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
  - Pemaquid seminar, 1960-1962 (Box 8)
  - Permission--anthology reprints, etc., 1970-1972 (Box 8)
  - Permissions, 1967-1970 (Box 8)
  - Poetry Magazine, 1961-1972 (Box 8)
  - Poetry Center, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Permissions for tapes, reprints, anthologies, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - The Abduction, 1971 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous magazines--current, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Speaking completed, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Serving as judge, 1973-1976 (Box 8)
  - Requests--poems, articles, reprints, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Norris, Joan, 1976-1978 (Box 8)
  - Oles, Carole, 1973, undated (Box 8)
  - Mewshaw, Mike, 1973-1977 (Box 8)
  - Friends, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Reprints to appear in copies of anthologies, 1973-1976 (Box 8)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1962-1979 (Box 8)
  - Fan mail, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
  - Bread Loaf, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Articles--newspaper and magazine, 1969-1978; 2 (Box 9)
  - National Endowment Task Force, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Brandeis, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Columbia University, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, literature panel, 1974-1977 (Box 9)
  - Bread Loaf lectures, undated (Box 9)
  - Bread Loaf--current, 1973-1976 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts Council on the Arts and Humanities, 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Speaking-completed, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Magazines, some good places to send stuff, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Lordly and Dame, 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Sacred Heart, 1971-1973 (Box 9)
  - Radcliffe Institute, independent study, 1968-1975 (Box 9)
  - Speaking completed--old, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
  - Harper and Row--current, 1972-1975 (Box 9)
  - Russell, Diarmuid, 1972-1973, undated (Box 9)
  - Godine, David, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
  - Requests--miscellaneous, 1975-1977 (Box 9)
  - Cole, Gloria, 1971-1978 (Box 9)
  - Laurie, 1973-1977, undated (Box 9)
  - Up Country, 1971-1974 (Box 9)
  - Glaze, Bunny, 1972-1976 (Box 9)
  - Flowers, Charlie, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Keules, Barbara, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Calendar, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Friends, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
  - Pulitzer Prize--correspondence, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Pulitzer clips, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum vitae (old stuff), 1973-1975 (Box 9)
  - Recommendations, 1976 (Box 9)
  - Robinowitz worksheets, undated (Box 9)
  - Worksheets, undated; 4 (Box 10)
  - Short stories--bone pile, 1969 (Box 10)
    Includes "The Monkey and the Malone"
  - Bone pile--adult poems, undated (Box 10)
  - Worksheets for certain poems, undated; 2 (Box 10)
  - Worksheets, undated (Box 10)
  - Worksheets (poems), 1977 (Box 10)
  - Translations--Kumin into French, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
  - Poem--worksheets, 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - Worksheets--poems, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Poems and worksheets--new, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Worksheets--fiction, 1977 (Box 10)
  - Short story in progress, undated (Box 10)
  - Anthology, 1969, undated (Box 10)
  - February-March journal (worksheets and carbon), 1978, undated (Box 10)
  - For Up Country, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1976 (Box 10)
  - Worksheets--prose essays, undated (Box 10)
  - Worksheets--poems, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
  - Essays--bone pile, undated (Box 10)
  - Bone pile--manuscript of The Heron, undated (Box 10)
  - Scientistics ( The Wonderful Babies of 1809 ), 1969 (Box 10)
  - Old poem worksheets, undated (Box 10)
  - Old poem bone pile, undated (Box 10)
  - The new novel, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Speech material--old, 1968, undated (Box 11)
  - Possibles--rough notes, 1975, undated (Box 11)
  - Radcliffe seminar recurrent themes, undated (Box 11)
  - Articles by Maxine Kumin; poems, 1975, undated (Box 11)
  - Early Kumin, undated (Box 11)
    Includes "Max Shulman's Zebra Derby", "Song of the Sabbath", and "Home of the Free"
  - Worksheets--poems, 1982 August; 2 (Box 11)
  - Newspaper clippings and printed material, 1969-1977 (Box 11)
  - Wright, Jay, 1968-1971; 2 (Box 11)
  - Speaking engagements--past, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Schraq, Peter, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Speaking--No, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Speaking engagements, 1971 (Box 11)
  - S, 1967-1968 (Box 11)
  - Saturday Review, 1965-1972 (Box 11)
  - Carel, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Carel correspondence, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Carel--spring workshops, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Newtown South high--Ms. Cornick, undated (Box 11)
  - Burning Tree School--thank you, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Boces - Tec, other educational experiments, 1968-1971 (Box 11)
  - Royalties, 1966-1969 (Box 11)
  - House, Bridge, Foundation, Gate, dust jacket, undated (Box 11)
  - Russell, Diarmuid, 1967-1971 (Box 11)
  - Royalties--all books Putnam, 1960-1967 (Box 11)
  - Calendars and receipts, 1968-1972 (Box 11)
  - Serving as judge or on boards, 1970-1972, undated (Box 12)
  - Up Country --advertisement, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Centre College, KY, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1975-1977 (Box 12)
  - Radcliffe College, 1972-1976 (Box 12)
  - Radcliffe--Society of Fellows, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Copyright, revisions of, 1976, undated (Box 12)
  - Poetry --Chicago, 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Radcliffe Quarterly, 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1972-1976 (Box 12)
  - American Poetry Review, 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Reviews-- The Designated Heir, 1974 (Box 12)
  - The Designated Heir, 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Fan mail, 1973-1975 (Box 12)
  - Fan mail--out, 1969-1976 (Box 12)
  - Job offers, 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Recommendations, 1973-1975 (Box 12)
  - Interviews, 1974, undated (Box 12)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1973-1974 (Box 12)
  - Speaking requests, 1973-1976 (Box 12)
  - Speaking requests--"no", 1974-1976 (Box 12)
  - Bicentennial, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
  - Articles, 1969-1973 (Box 12)
  - University of Massachusetts, 1972-1974 (Box 12)
  - Speaking engagements, 1970 (Box 12)
  - Radcliffe Institute independent study, 1960-1964 (Box 12)
  - Lectures, undated (Box 12)
  - Commencement--Davis & Elkins College, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Centre College--notes for commencement address, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Introduction for Sheila Nickerson, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Nation article, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - "Influences" essay for Joyce Carol Oates, 1983 (Box 12)
  - "A Squeeze Around the Neck", 1963 (Box 13)
  - Poetry Column-- The Writer magazine, 1962-1964; 2 (Box 13)
  - Library of Congress introductions, undated (Box 13)
  - Library of Congress lecture--American Women Between World War One and Two, 1981 May (Box 13)
  - Manuscript article, 1982, undated (Box 13)
  - Country Kitchen piece, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Essay for Stephen Berg's book, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Film script, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Poet's responsibility lecture, 1984, undated (Box 13)
  - Poet's responsibility lecture--worksheets and draft, 1983, undated (Box 13)
  - Georgia Review essay, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Salzburg-- Georgia Review essay, 1985 (Box 13)
  - O. Henry lecture, 1985 (Box 13)
  - O. Henry Society talk with poems, worksheets, and drafts, undated (Box 13)
  - Highland article and information, 1981, undated (Box 13)
  - Short story book for Viking, undated (Box 13)
    Includes "To Be of Use", "The Perfect Body", "Facts of Life", Why Can't We Live Together Like Civilized Human Beings?, "Other Nations", "A Traveler's Hello", and "The Banquet"
  - Short stories--bone pile and some carbons, 1977-1978, undated (Box 13)
    Includes "The Moveable Secretary", "Winering Over", "The Accident", "The Visit", and "The Town Records Its Deaths"
  - "The Sound Post", undated (Box 13)
  - "These Gifts", 1975-1976, undated (Box 13)
  - "The Missing Person" (short story), undated (Box 13)
  - "Other Nations"--short story, 1981 (Box 13)
  - "Other Nations" -- worksheets (story), undated (Box 13)
  - "The Fat Girl", 1962-1965 (Box 13)
  - "The Town Records Its Death" (story), undated (Box 13)
  - "Another Form of Marriage", undated (Box 13)
  - "A Traveler's Hello", undated (Box 13)
  - "Crossing the Line", 1974, undated (Box 13)
  - "Taming the Joplin Place", undated (Box 13)
  - "Facts of Life" (story) worksheets, undated (Box 13)
  - "The Banquet" (short story), 1977 (Box 13)
  - "Sebastian and the Dragon Meet the Unicorn", 1960, undated (Box 13)
  - "A Taste of Happiness", undated (Box 13)
  - Langston Hughes, undated (Box 13)
  - "The Murder of Agrippina", undated (Box 13)
  - "This Is Benjamin", 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - "The Keeper of His Beasts", 1962 (Box 13)
  - "The Consciousness-Raising of Robin Parks", undated (Box 13)
  - "Buying the Child", undated (Box 13)
  - Story written in early '40s? (High school), 1940s (Box 13)
  - "Elmer's Easy Eggs", 1961 (Box 13)
  - "The Wonderful Adventure of Jenny Devotion", 1962 April 2 (Box 14)
  - "Clara Barton", undated (Box 14)
  - "Danny's Hurricane Luck", 1961-1963 (Box 14)
  - "The Wounded Cardinal", undated (Box 14)
  - "The Neutral Love Object" (story), 1973 (Box 14)
  - "The Moveable Secretary", undated (Box 14)
  - "The Primal Scene", 1973, undated (Box 14)
  - "The Mary Jane Kitchen", undated (Box 14)
  - Bread Loaf lectures, very old, 1971, undated (Box 14)
  - Essays--miscellaneous, 1968-1983 (Box 14)
  - "On This Short Day of Frost and Sun" (short story), undated (Box 14)
  - "Opening the Door on 62nd Street", 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Lost Women lecture, American Antiquarian Society, Worcester, MA, 1981 April 16 (Box 14)
  - Notes for '82 Library of Congress lecture, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Translations--correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 14)
  - Translations--done, undated (Box 14)
  - Translations--all poets except Cliff, undated (Box 14)
  - Cliff book, also requests for individual Cliff poems, 1977-1978 (Box 14)
  - Cliff book, undated (Box 14)
  - Cliff drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - Field Magazine, 1979 June 2 (Box 14)
  - Translations--correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 14)
  - "The Poet and the Mule," information and worksheets, 1979, undated (Box 14)
  - Mushroom book--Paul Zimmer--Dead. Use elsewhere., 1978, undated (Box 14)
  - Mushroom article, undated (Box 14)
  - Theodore, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Biographical material--bibliography, 1975 (Box 14)
  - "Scientistics"--early manusripts and xeroxes, undated (Box 14)
  - Godine horse book, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Manuscript article--"Women and Horses", undated (Box 14)
  - "The Poet and the Mule," article, 1983 (Box 14)
  - The Microscope, book, 1983-1985 (Box 14)
  - The Microscope --manuscript and front matter, undated (Box 14)
  - William Cliff and other translations from French and proposed manuscript for a Cliff book, undated (Box 14)
  - William Cliff and other translations from French and proposed manuscript for a Cliff book, 1976, undated; 2 (Box 15)
  - Speaking--completed, current year, 1973-1974 (Box 15)
  - "To Make a Prairie", 1980 (Box 15)
  - Lyle, Katie, 1973-1975 (Box 15)
  - Writers, unknown, struggling, etc., 1975 (Box 15)
  - Requests--poems, manuscripts, reprints, 1973-1975 (Box 15)
  - Judy Moyer, 1977-1980 (Box 15)
  - Steve, 1971-1977 (Box 15)
  - Jules Halljm, 1972-1977 (Box 15)
  - Map/directions to Warner, undated (Box 15)
  - Wang, Joan, 1968-1979 (Box 15)
  - Wakefield, 1970-1975 (Box 15)
  - Rust, 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - The New Yorker, 1973-1979 (Box 15)
  - Friends, old--frequent correspondents (non-poets), 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Princeton, 1980 (Box 15)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1979-1983 (Box 15)
  - Students, would-be writers from speaking engagements, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Farm, 1983-1985 (Box 15)
  - Friends, old; non-poets; friends of the family, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Fans, casual friends, 1984-1985 (Box 15)
  - Pulitzer Prize 1984 manuscript, 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Library of Congress--general, 1981-1984 (Box 16)
  - Speaking completed, 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - "The Poet and the Mule", bibliography, 1970, undated (Box 16)
  - Poetry worksheets for exhibit, undated (Box 16)
  - Bulgarian translations (for Balaban), 1985 (Box 16)
  - Appletree Alley--fine editions--Taylor--Wheatcroft, 1983-1985 (Box 16)
  - Royalties, 1970-1972 (Box 16)
  - Sweeney, Jack, 1961-1962 (Box 16)
  - Ann Sperber, 1968-1970 (Box 16)
  - Tri-Quarterly, 1964-1971 (Box 16)
  - Annie Wilder, 1964-1973 (Box 16)
  - Teaching Anthology--poems, undated (Box 16)
  - Tapes, reprints, anthologies, 1963-1967 (Box 16)
  - Postcard from Jack, 1960 (Box 16)
  - Royalties, 1972-1974 (Box 16)
  - Requests for poems and manuscripts, 1967-1972 (Box 16)
  - Recommendations, 1968-1972 (Box 16)
  - Requests--miscellaneous, 1973-1974, undated (Box 16)
  - Income, 1983 (Box 16)
  - USIA trip, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Ross, Mary Beth, 1978-1982, undated (Box 16)